## Thiti (Pob) Vutisalchavakul

Passionate Learner

## **Personal Info**

Location

Remote / NYC

**Phone** 

937-846-6809

E-mail

Vutisat@MiamiOH.edu

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/vutisat/

Twitter @Pob\_V

# Programming Languages

#### **Strong**

JVM Languages (Java, Groovy)

#### **Proficient**

Python, JavaScript (Typescript, Node, React / Redux, D3, C3), GraphQL, HTML, CSS, SQL, NoSQL

#### **Exposed To**

C++, Prolog, Scheme, Racket, R

## **Technologies**

#### **Strong**

Micro-services Architecture, Spring Boot, Spock

#### **Proficient**

MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Kubernetes, Snowflake, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Docker, Drone, ELK Stack, Networking, PCF/Azure

#### **Exposed To**

AWS, HAProxy, Nginx, Memcahed, Redis, Hadoop Ecosystem, Android Development, Building Als

## **Other Skills**

- Strong business and leadership skills
- Experienced in conducting usability studies
- Design Thinking
- Agile Methodology
- Test-driven Development (TDD)
- Extensive international travel background, comfortable with traveling and working with and in different cultures (Bilingual: Thai/English)

Puns, Jokes, and Memes

Energetic Technology Leader with a passion in continuous learning and leading high-performing teams.

Experienced in guiding product initiatives, from new ideas to fully-released, adopted, and supported products.

Entrusted with writing clean & robust code at scale. (petabytes of data, millions of hits per day, billions-of-dollars systems).

Celebrated as a servant leader and for creating a fun culture that brings the best out of others.

## **Experience**

## **Senior Software Engineer – Datasite**

Summer 2018 - Present

- Developed and maintained a highly sensitive billing system that directly impacts the company's bottom-line and thousands of clients.
  - → Processed billions of dollars, with accuracy down to every penny
- Created an internal library that allowed data capturing of every activity on the application, used by many team
  - → Petabytes of data warehouse used for analytics as well as generating SOX-report (FEC)
- Created a secure email-service for which the firm uses for all outgoing emails
- Lead a team to develop and deliver the new landing page of Datasite that not only completely revolutionized the look & feel of the application but streamlined its usage by providing insightful analytics and real-time notifications.
- Lead contributor for Datasite's latest product, Outreach.
  - → Created various GraphQL, Node, and SpringBoot APIs → Implemented data integration system with Salesforce
  - → Orchestrated an infrastructure for production-readiness of the application (Set up monitors/alerts, trained app-support teams, ensured system scales efficiently, etc.)
- Contributed in various major architectural decision for the organization as well as helped mentor developers.

## **Software Engineer - TARGET**

**Summer 2016 - Summer 2018** 

- Implemented a functionality in the Target.com's data aggregator to deliver the an item's prices in stores in real time
  - → Over 10 million hits per day, with 95%+ of response time being less than 1 second
- Worked with UX designers to render the front-end for Social Migration of Non-Target registered accounts in the Cartwheel app to switch to Target Accounts
  - → Experienced by 15 million users
- Spearheaded a software project that has allowed Target to expedite \$100k+ of orders (and rising), as a full-stack engineer. Full software development cycle, end-to-end
- Stood up a new API that allowed the Target Mobile Apps to display locations of items to guests.
- Utilized C3.js and D3.js to visualize data in an elegant way for consumers of the Target's Big Data Platform (Hadoop) to monitor and see their usage on the cluster as a whole

#### **Lockheed Martin Leadership Institute**

Fall 2013 - Summer 2016

- Three-year certificate program that develops technical/innovative leadership, business acumen, people leadership and personal/ethical leadership
- Developed and practiced leadership skills through workshops, projects, and meetings with business executives from multiple Fortune 500 companies
- Ignited an effort to help fight stereotypes of engineers that lead to a global trending of #IAmAnEngineer on Twitter

## Software Engineer - StudySync (McGraw-Hill Education)

Fall 2015 – Summer 2016

- Developed a system for users to log into a third-party API to access their library of books matching the courses offered by StudySync; used CoffeeScript along with Node.js, AngularJS
- Implemented myriad front-end features directly from the feedback of teachers and students

## **Education**

#### **Farmer School of Business**

Con

Completed: January 2021

**Graduated: June 2016** 

Mini-MBA

## **Miami University**

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

- Theta Tau Engineering Fraternity: Petition Director, Marketing Chair Active Member of Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)
- UNICEF Campus Initiative: Help raised thousands of dollars annually Miami University High School Programming Contest: Judge

## **Activities**

- **Mentoring** Partnered with Genesys Works and mentored high school students in underserved communities through skills trains, sharing experiences, and creating impactful relationships
- **Volunteering** Enjoyed various volunteering activities with Habitat for Humanity, Feed My Starving Children, Engineers Without Borders, Great River Greening, etc.